Lead Marketing Scientist @ Yum! Brands.

+91 8700996752



I have 4.6 years of experience in Data Warehousing, Market Mix Modelling, Develop and Testing of ETL jobs, Data Analysis, Data Mart, Dashboard using Power BI/ SAS VA, Spend Analytics, Customer Analytics and Data Analytics (Predictive) Using Python and SAS. Also has experience in Development and Testing of MMM Models to predict the Sales. Deep Understanding in SAS AML Solution dataflow and data models. I have used the machine learning Algorithms to turn the data into actionable insights, analyze the data for trends, Patterns and data interpretation.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Lead Marketing Scientist**

Yum Brands!

09/2021 - Present

- My primary role involves designing, implementing, and interpreting regression models that estimate the impact of various marketing channels, such as TV, digital, print, and outdoor advertising, on sales and
- In addition to Market Mix Modelling, I also specialize in Market Basket Analysis and Customer Segmentation. Using these techniques, I analyze consumer transaction data to identify patterns and insights about customer behavior and preferences.

Tools Used: Excel, Python, Predictive Analytics, Statistical Data Analysis, Regression Models

#### Sr. Data Analyst

#### **Techieaze Consultancy Services**

01/2021 - 08/2021

- ETL Design and development to load the data into SAS Core
- Develop and test the 13 new AML 7.1 scenarios as per business logic
- Development and Testing of more than 80 new CDD rules as per business logic

Tools Used: SAS DI, SAS SMC, SAS EG, SAS AML, SAS CDD, SAS Viya, Python

#### Data Analyst

#### **Techieaze Consultancy Services**

10/2020 - 12/2020

- Developed a Data Mart to find the intermediate Accounts involve in the Fraud within given date.
- Developed Sankey diagram to visualize the flow of transaction between two or more fraudulent accounts, Using Power BI / SAS Viya
- Developing around 15-20 interactive Dashboards as per Client requirement in SAS VA using SAS Viya Platform

Tools Used: SAS Data Studio, Power BI, SAS Viya, Excel, Python

## Data Management/Analysis/ AML 7.1, Abu Dhabi (Onsite/Offshore)

**Techieaze Consultancy Services** 

09/2018 - 09/2020

- Developed ETL for data cleansing and loading the data in Core
- Developed SAS macro to generate the data reconciliation report

Tools Used: SAS EG, Base, AML

## **EDUCATION**

## Master of Computer Applications

ITS Ghaziabad UP

07/2017 - 04/2019

Passing Percentage 78%

# **Bachelor of Computer Applications**

08/2014 - 05/2017

ITS Ghaziabad UP

## **SKILLS**



## CERTIFICATION

Analytics Using SAS (2021)

From Great Lerning

Machine Learning With Python (2021)

From Great Learning

### **TRAINING**

SAS Training (08/2018 - 01/2019)

SAS Base, SAS EG, SAS DI, SAS AML

SAS (Analytics) (02/2019 - 03/2019)

Created a SAS Model to do the churn prediction for a telecom company

Python Training (08/2019 - 09/2019)

Python for data Analytics (Pandas, Numpy)

Alteryx Training (10/2020 - 11/2020)

Created ETL's to load the data into DWH, Created Predictive models as the part of Training

Apache Airflow (11/2020 - 12/2020)

Learn how Apache Airflow can help to orchestrate the ETL flow and Machine learning Model

#### LANGUAGES

SAS Base

Professional Working Proficiency

SOL

Full Professional Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

Movies

Elementary Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

Sports

Passing Percentage 82%